SUCHIRA DHAR

University of Limerick, Co. Limerick, Ireland +

+353 899655496

■ suchiraofficial@gmail.com

LINKEDIN https://www.linkedin.com/in/suchiradhar/

Intera	action	Bl	JX	Des	igner

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With a career spanning over 10 years, including 4+ years dedicated to UI/UX design, I help build brands for startups and multinationals. As a Masters of Interaction and Experience Design student at UL, my disciplines of study include mobile (wearable) interactions, 3D modelling & animation, AR/VR, psychology and HCI. My multidisciplinary background, strategic approach and creative pursuits inspire me to bring forth a unique perspective to human interactions with machines.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

\	User Journey	\checkmark	Information Architecture	\checkmark	Usability Testing
	,	•			9

✓ Wireframing
✓ Design Systems
✓ Research

✓ Prototyping
✓ Branding
✓ Communication

SKILLS & TOOLS

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD	Framer, HTML/CSS
Adobe Photoshop	Maya
After Effects	Unity

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UX Designer, ARC Document Solutions - Kolkata, West Bengal Jan 2023 - June 2024

- Planning and implementing new designs for projects such as ARC Print, Skysite Archives, and ARC Facilities.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to enhance project workflows, and improving coordination.
- Optimising and testing existing user interface designs for intuitiveness and experience.
- Building functional design systems that align with project guidelines and responsiveness.
- Communicating with stakeholders to understand business goals and objectives.
- Developing technical and business requirements and striving to deliver intuitive and user-centred solutions.
- Creating prototypes for new product ideas.
- Conducting user research and applying user-centred design principles as per HCl and HFl guidelines.
- Developing interaction design and information architectures.

UI/UX Designer (Contractual), Lane 4 Solution - Surat, Gujarat

October 2020 - December 2022

- Producing end-to-end design solutions by understanding client requirements and project objectives.
- Delivering brand guidelines, assets, wireframes and responsive mockups.
- Incorporating post-testing changes to optimise product performance.
- Developing landing pages for marketing campaigns that align with brand guidelines and target audience.
- Conducting competitor analysis and suggesting relevant improvements to enhance user experiences.
- Ensuring timely completion of assigned projects and effectively coordinating all design materials with cross functional teams to achieve project goals.

Operations Manager & Copywriter, Blindspot Media Pvt. Ltd. - Guwahati, Assam

September 2019 - August 2020

- Maintaining communication with management, team members, and clients.
- Ensuring timely operational activities and deliveries.
- Growing the efficiency of existing organisational processes and procedures.
- Identifying customer needs and recommending new content to address gaps in communication.
- Conducting keyword research and using SEO best practices to increase traffic to websites.
- Developing and proofreading content for blogs, articles, product descriptions, social media, and websites.

Music Instructor, Soundmonk School Of Music - Mumbai, Maharashtra

February 2016 - July 2019

- Planning curriculum and preparing lessons in relation to individual students' needs and examination syllabuses.
- Teaching music theory, aural skills and practical techniques to pupils entering and preparing pupils for examinations.
- Preparing appropriate teaching materials and resources.
- Assessing pupils' abilities, providing feedback and writing reports.
- Obtained Trinity College of London (Voice) Certification.

Graphic Designer, The Country Roads - Kolkata, West Bengal

March 2013 - February 2015

- Planning concepts by studying relevant information and materials related to tourism and competitors.
- Illustrating concepts by designing examples of art arrangement, size, type size and style.
- Preparing finished art by operating necessary equipment and Adobe software tools.
- Coordinating and communicating with web designers, marketing, printers and colleagues for layout and designs.
- Creating and improving upon a wide range of graphics and layouts for product illustrations, company logos and website assets.

Graphic Designer, Gopa Gupta - Kolkata, West Bengal

August 2011 - February 2013

- Creating graphics and design layouts for marketing and promotional materials.
- Collaborating with design and marketing teams to produce high-quality print and digital assets, including brochures, posters, social media graphics and website elements.
- Supporting in designing and editing images, illustrations and multimedia content to align with brand identity.
- Contributing creative ideas and participating in brainstorming to enhance product marketing.

EDUCATION

Masters of Interaction and Experience Design

Current

University of Limerick, *Ireland*

Bachelor of Arts (Psychology)

June 2023

Indira Gandhi National Open University (IGNOU), Delhi, India

Total 67.46%

Vocal Performer Certificate Program

July 2017

The True School of Music, Mumbai, India

Total 94%

Class XII (Science)

2011

Srimanta Shankar Academy, Assam, India

Total 80.2%

Class X

2009

B.K. Bajoria School, Meghalaya, India

Total 89%

CERTIFICATIONS

Digital Skills: User Experience

November 2022

Accenture

Google UX Certificate

April 2022

Coursera

INTERESTS

- Artwork and Illustrations
- Exploring new design tools
- Writing poetry and articles
- Music and playing piano